坦格利安王朝的第一个世纪
As the first century of the Targaryen dynasty
已近尾声
came to a close
人瑞王杰赫里斯一世的身体状况每况愈下
the health of the Old King, Jaehaerys, was failing.
那段岁月里 坦格利安家族轭下尚有十条成年巨龙
In those days, House Targaryen stood at the height of its strength
家族势力如日中天
with ten adult dragons under its yoke.
世间无人可与之抗衡
No power in the world could stand against it.
杰赫里斯国王的统治近六十年
King Jaehaerys reigned over nearly 60 years
王国和平而繁荣
of peace and prosperity
未曾想悲剧夺走了他的长子和次子的性命
but tragedy had claimed both his sons
使得继承人成了疑问
leaving his succession in doubt.
于是在征服101年
So, in the year 101
人瑞王召开大议会来选定继承人
the Old King called a Great Council to choose an heir.
上千领主赶赴赫伦堡
Over a thousand lords made the journey to Harrenhal.
十四位继承人选参与听证
Fourteen succession claims were heard
但真正的竞争者只有两位
but only two were truly considered.
雷妮丝·坦格利安公主 国王最年长的后裔
Princess Rhaenys Targaryen, the King's eldest descendant
和她的堂弟 韦赛里斯·坦格利安王子
and her younger cousin, Prince Viserys Targaryen
国王最年长的男性后裔
the King's eldest male descendant.
七大王国所有大小领主
It is declared by all lords paramount
和下属封臣共同宣布
and lords vassal of the Seven Kingdoms
韦赛里斯·坦格利安王子获封龙石岛亲王！
that Prince Viserys Targaryen be made Prince of Dragonstone!
雷妮丝身为女人 无缘继承铁王座
Rhaenys, a woman, would not inherit the Iron Throne.
领主们选择了韦赛里斯
The lords instead chose Viserys
我的父亲
my father.
杰赫里斯召开大议会
Jaehaerys called the Great Council
避免了因继承权而掀起战争
to prevent a war being fought over his succession.
只因他知晓那个冷酷的真相
For he knew the cold truth.
能摧毁龙王家族的
The only thing that could tear down the House of the Dragon
只有它自己
was itself.
这是韦赛里斯一世在位的第九年
此时离疯王伊里斯过世
及其女儿丹妮莉丝·坦格利安公主出生 还有172年
离
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安        出生 还有172年
听话 叙拉克斯！
Dohaerās, Syrax!
等等
Umbās.
乖！
Rȳbās!
欢迎回来 公主 相信您骑得很过瘾
Welcome back, Princess. I trust your ride was pleasant.
别故作轻松了 爵士
Try not to look too relieved, ser.
我是真的轻松
I am relieved.
每次那只金色巨兽带您安然无恙地回来
Every time that golden beast brings you back unspoiled
我的脑袋又逃过一次枪尖
it saves my head from a spike.
叙拉克斯长得很快
Syrax is growing quickly.
她很快就和科拉克休一样大了
She'll soon be as large as Caraxes.
大到可以放上双人龙鞍
That's almost large enough to saddle two.
我确信我在一旁当个观众就很满足了 谢谢
I believe I'm quite content as a spectator, thank you.
听话
Dohaerās.
往前！
Naejot!
雷妮拉
Rhaenyra.
你知道我现在这个情况下
You know I don't like you to go flying
不喜欢你去骑龙
while I'm in this condition.
你在任何情况下都不喜欢我骑龙
You don't like me to go flying while you're in any condition.
- 王后陛下 - 早 阿莉森
- Your Grace. - Good morrow, Alicent.
你睡了吗？
Did you sleep?
- 睡了 - 睡了多久？
- I slept. - How long?
我不需要你来当老妈 雷妮拉
I don't need mothering, Rhaenyra.
但你周围这些服侍的人
Well, here you are, surrounded by attendants
都只关心你肚子里的宝宝
all focused on the babe.
总得有人关心你
Someone has to attend to you.
很快你也会躺在这张床上 雷妮拉
You will lie in this bed soon enough, Rhaenyra.
这种煎熬就是我们服务王国的方式
This discomfort is how we serve the realm.
我宁愿身为骑士驰骋疆场 去赢得荣誉
I'd rather serve as a knight and ride to battle and glory.
我们的子宫属于王室 你和我都是
We have royal wombs, you and I.
产床就是我们的战场
The childbed is our battlefield.
我们必须学会咬牙面对
We must learn to face it with a stiff lip.
现在去洗个澡
Now take a bath.
你臭得像条龙
You stink of dragon.
于是我对他说 我相信你
So, I said to him, "Well, I believe
应该看看另一端
you might be looking up the wrong end."
大人们
My lords.
自由贸易城邦的联盟正在壮大
The growing alliance among the Free Cities
开始自称三女儿王国
has taken to styling itself the Triarchy.
他们在血石岛聚集
They have massed on Bloodstone
目前正在驱除盘踞在石阶列岛
and are presently ridding the Stepstones
的那些海盗
of its pirate infestation.
听起来倒像是个好消息 科利斯大人
Well, that sounds suspiciously like good news, Lord Corlys.
有个叫克拉哈斯·达哈尔的家伙
A man called Craghas Drahar
自称三女儿王国的海军上将亲王
has styled himself the prince-admiral of this Triarchy.
别人叫他螃蟹喂食者
They call him the Crabfeeder
缘于他颇有创意的处死敌人的方式
due to his inventive methods of punishing his enemies.
难道我们要为海盗们哀悼吗？
And are we meant to weep for dead pirates?
- 不 陛下 - 雷妮拉 你迟到了
- No, Your Grace. - Rhaenyra, you're late.
国王的侍酒可不能迟到
The King's cupbearer must not be late.
- 大人们都渴了 - 我去看望母亲了
- Leaves people wanting for cups. - I was visiting Mother.
骑龙去的？
On dragonback?
陛下 戴蒙王子一直敦促国库
Hey, Your Grace, at Prince Daemon's urging
拨巨款给他的都城守备队
the crown has invested significant capital
以加强训练和升级装备
in the re-training and re-equipping of his City Watch.
我认为您也应该敦促您弟弟出席御前会议
I thought you might urge your brother to fill his seat on the council
作为都城守备队队长
and provide an assessment of his progress
向我们汇报工作进度
as commander of the Watch.
你不觉得戴蒙现在沉迷于工作
Do you think Daemon is distracted by his present tasks?
既能释放精力 又无暇他顾也不错吗？
And that his thoughts and energies are occupied?
希望如此 毕竟我们付出了不少成本
Well, one would hope so, considering the associated costs.
那就当你花的钱是笔划算的投资吧 毕斯柏里大人
Then let us all consider your gold well-invested, Lord Beesbury.
我认为您不能再纵容三女儿王国
I would urge that you not allow this Triarchy much latitude
在石阶列岛为所欲为了 陛下
in the Stepstones, Your Grace.
一旦航道受阻 会让我们的港口难以为继
If those shipping lanes should fall, it will beggar our ports.
国王已经听到你的谏言了 科利斯大人
The crown has heard your report, Lord Corlys
会认真考虑的
and takes it under advisement.
我们来谈谈王储比武大会吧 陛下
Shall we discuss the Heir's Tournament, Your Grace?
我十分乐意
I would be delighted.
学士们预测的命名日可靠吗 梅罗斯
Will the maesters' name day prediction hold, Mellos?
您要明白这毕竟只是预测 陛下
You must understand that these things are mere estimations, my King
但我们在月表上呕心沥血
but we have all been poring over the moon charts
相信我们的预测已经尽可能精确
and we feel that our forecast is as accurate as it can be.
比武大会的开销巨大
The cost of the tournament is not negligible.
或许我们可以推迟至孩子出生后再开始？
Perhaps we might delay until the child is in hand?
大多数领主和骑士
Most of the lords and knights
都已经在赶往君临的路上
are certainly on their way to King's Landing already.
- 现在让他们回去…… - 比武大会将持续
- To turn them back now... - The tourney will take
大半个星期
the better part of a week.
在比武大会结束前  我儿子便出生了
Before the games are over, my son will be born
整个国家将为之庆祝
and the whole realm will celebrate.
我们还无法预测孩子的性别
We have no way of predicting the sex of the child.
当然 没有学士会在缺乏依据的情况下
Of course, no maester's capable of rendering an opinion
做出判断 是吧？
free of conditions, are they now?
王后肚子里怀的是男孩
There's a boy in the Queen's belly.
我知道
I know it.
而我的继承人很快就会
And my heir will soon put all of this
亲自平息这一切糟心事
damnable hand-wringing to rest himself.
天一亮他就穿过了红堡大门
He passed through the Red Keep's gates at first light.
我父亲知道他来了吗？
Does my father know he's here?
- 不知道 - 好的
- No. - Good.
诸神慈悲
Gods be good.
没事的 爵士
It's all right, ser.
你在做什么 叔叔？
Sparo drīvose gaomā, kepus?
随意坐坐
Ñuhoso dēman.
说不定哪天这就是我的椅子了
Kesy ñuhys dēmavos māzīlariot sinilus.
除非你想被处以煽动叛国罪
Lo hen pāleknot statilūks, daor.
你好久没来宫廷了
Hen sȳndrāzmā qurdalbri imastō daor.
是的
Aye.
宫廷里无聊透顶
Qurdalbar gierī tegenkor issa.
那你为什么还回来？
Sepār vēzo gō skoro syt āmastā?
我听说你父亲要以我的名义举办一场比武大会
Kepa aōha yno syt kōttion pradilas, ryptan.
那是为他的继承人举办的比武大会
Kōttion dāranno syt issa.
这不就是我的意思嘛
Heksīr ȳdratan.
他的新继承人
Dāranno zȳho arlio syt.
除非你母亲生下一个儿子
Iā aōha muña trēsi sikos,
你们被我缠定了
iā jevo yrgoti zbērion.
那我倒是希望能有个弟弟
Sepār valonqri jaelinna.
我带了个礼物给你
I bought you something.
你知道这是什么吗？
Do you know what it is?
瓦雷利亚钢
It's Valyrian steel.
和黑暗姐妹一样
Like Dark Sister.
转过身去
Turn around.
现在
Now
你和我都拥有了我们祖先的一小块物品
you and I both own a small piece of our ancestry.
真美
Gevie.
- 你看书了吗？ -  我当然看了
- Did you read it? - Of course, I read it.
娜梅莉亚公主到了多恩以后
When Princess Nymeria arrived in Dorne
选择的丈夫是谁？
who did she take to husband?
一个男的
A man.
他的名字是？
What was his name?
某某大人
Lord Something.
如果你拿“某某大人”当答案 玛洛修女得气疯了
If you answer with "Lord Something," Septa Marlow will be furious.
她生起气来可好玩了
She's funny when she's furious.
你有心事的时候就是现在这样
You're always like this when you're worried.
哪样？
Like what?
不好相处
Disagreeable.
你担心你父亲会因为有了儿子
You're worried your father is about to overshadow you
而忽略你
with a son.
我只是替我母亲担心
I only worry for my mother.
我希望父亲能有个儿子
I hope for my father that he gets a son.
从我记事开始 这就是他一直想要的
As long as I can recall, it's all he's wanted.
你希望他有儿子？
You want him to have a son?
我希望能和你一起骑龙
I want to fly with you on dragonback
飞越狭海 看看那边的奇观
see the great wonders across the Narrow Sea
还希望只吃蛋糕
and eat only cake.
- 我是认真的 - 我从不拿蛋糕开玩笑
- I'm being serious. - I never jest about cake.
你不担心你的位置吗？
You aren't worried about your position?
我喜欢现在的位置 非常舒服
I like this position. It's quite comfortable.
你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
回家 时间晚了
Home. The hour has grown late.
娜梅莉亚公主带领洛伊拿人乘坐一万艘船横渡狭海
Princess Nymeria led her Rhoynar across the Narrow Sea on 10,000 ships
以躲避瓦雷利亚人的追捕
to flee their Valyrian pursuers.
她选了多恩的莫尔斯·马泰尔作丈夫
She took Lord Mors Martell of Dorne to husband
在阳戟城下烧毁了她的整支舰队
and burned her own fleet off Sunspear
以宣告她的子民从今以后无需逃亡
to show her people that they were finished running.
- 你在干嘛？ - 这样你才能记住
- What are you doing? - So you remember.
- 如果修女看到这本书 那…… - 去他妈的修女
- If the Septa sees this book then... - Fuck the Septa.
雷妮拉！
Rhaenyra!
在愈合了吗？
Is it healing?
愈合得很慢 陛下
It has grown slightly, Your Grace.
现在知道这是什么了吗？
Can you say yet what it is?
我们已经向学城发信询问
We've sent inquiries to the Citadel.
他们正在书中查找相似的案例
They are searching the texts for similar cases.
这只是被王座割开的细小伤口
It's a small cut from sitting the throne.
没什么大事
It's nothing.
国王承受了巨大的压力
The King has been under heavy stresses
因为要为新生儿作准备
preparing for the birth.
不良的精神状态会对身体造成不好的影响
Bad humors of the mind can adversely affect the body.
不论是什么事 都不要声张
Whatever it is, it needs to be kept quiet.
我们应该再用水蛭放血 学士
We should leech it again, maester.
这伤口无法愈合 大学士
It's a wound that refuses to heal, Grand Maester.
我能否建议用烧灼疗法试试？
Might I suggest cauterization?
烧灼疗法也许是明智之举 陛下
Cauterization would be a wise course of treatment, Your Grace.
- 只是那会很疼…… - 好吧
- It will be painful... - Fine.
就这样
Fine.
你泡在浴缸里的时间比我坐在铁王座上的时间还久
You spend more time in that bath than I do on the throne.
这是这些天来唯一一处让我感到舒适的地方
This is the only place I can find comfort these days.
只有一点温
It's tepid.
学士们不允许更烫
It's as warm as the maesters will allow.
他们难道不知道龙喜欢热吗？
Don't they know dragons prefer heat?
经历这次痛苦的孕期后
After this miserable pregnancy
我若生出一条真龙 都不觉得奇怪了
I wouldn't be surprised if I hatched an actual dragon.
那他会受到疼爱和珍视
Then he will be loved and cherished.
雷妮拉已经宣布自己会有个妹妹了
Rhaenyra has already declared that she is to have a sister.
真的么？
Really?
- 她甚至为她取好了名字. - 我能问吗？
- She even named her. - Dare I ask?
维桑尼亚
Visenya.
她已经选好了放进摇篮的龙蛋
She chose a dragon's egg for the cradle
她说这枚蛋让她想起了瓦格哈尔
that she said reminded her of Vhagar.
诸神慈悲
Gods be good.
这个家庭已经有了个维桑尼亚
This family already has its Visenya.
有你亲爱的弟弟的消息吗？
Has there been any word from your dear brother?
自从任命他为都城守备队司令后就没个信了
Not since I named him Commander of the City Watch.
我相信他一定会出现在比武大会
I'm sure he will reemerge for the tourney.
他向来无法拒绝亲自参赛
He could never stay away from the lists.
比武大会
The tourney
为庆祝我们还未出世的长子而办
to celebrate the firstborn son that we presently do not have.
你得明白
You do understand
如果宝宝本身没有小鸡鸡
nothing will cause the babe to grow a cock
也没什么办法硬长出来吧？
if it does not already possess one?
这是个男孩 爱玛
This child is a boy, Aemma.
我很确定
I'm certain of it.
我从来没有这么确定过
I've never been more certain of anything.
那个梦
The dream.
比记忆还清晰
It was clearer than a memory.
我们的儿子戴着伊耿的王冠降生
Our son was born wearing Aegon's iron crown.
我听到雷鸣般的马蹄声
When I heard the sound of thundering hooves
盾牌破碎和挥剑的声音
splintering shields, and ringing swords
我把我们的儿子放在铁王座上
and I placed our son upon the Iron Throne
圣堂的钟声响起 所有巨龙齐声而吼
as the bells of the Grand Sept tolled and all the dragons roared as one.
戴着王冠出生？
Born wearing a crown?
诸神救救我吧 生孩子已经很难受了
Gods spare me, birth is unpleasant enough as it is.
这是最后一次了吗 韦赛里斯
This is the last time, Viserys.
我有个宝宝死于襁褓 生下过两个死胎
I've lost one babe in the cradle, had two stillbirths
还有两次怀孕在足月前就结束了
and two pregnancies ended well before their term.
五个孩子 前后耗费了十年
That's five in twice as many years.
我知道 为你生下继承人是我的责任
I know it is my duty to provide you an heir
如果为此让你失望了 我很抱歉
and I'm sorry if I have failed you in that.
真的很抱歉
I am.
但我没法再悼念更多死去的孩子了
But I've mourned all the dead children I can.
司令到场！
Commander on the floor!
当我接下都城守备队司令一职时 你们还是一群
When I took command of the Watch, you were stray mongrels
饥饿散漫的野狗
starving and undisciplined.
如今 你们成为了一队猎犬
Now, you're a pack of hounds.
酒足饭饱 历经磨练 随时可以狩猎
You're sated and honed for the hunt.
我哥哥的城市已经变得堕落不堪
My brother's city has fallen into squalor.
各种罪行肆意滋生 猖獗横行
Crime of every breed has been allowed to thrive.
这种日子到头了
No longer.
从今晚起
Beginning tonight
君临将学会畏惧金色
King's Landing will learn to fear the color gold.
起身！
Get up!
强奸犯！
Raper!
不！不要……不！
No! No... no!
小偷！
Thief!
不！
No!
杀人犯！
Murderer!
这是一次对各类犯罪的空前围捕
It was an unprecedented roundup of criminals of every ilk.
你弟弟当众做秀
Your brother made a public show of it
亲自做出裁决
meting out the summary judgments himself.
我听说他们得用双驾马车
I'm told they needed a two-horse cart
才拉走了所有被肢解的人体
to haul away the resulting dismemberments when it was done.
诸神慈悲
Gods be good.
不能让王子如此肆无忌惮 还逍遥法外
The Prince cannot be allowed to act with this kind of unchecked impunity.
- 哥哥 - 戴蒙
- Brother. - Daemon.
继续啊 你刚正说我逍遥法外的事
Carry on. You were saying something about my impunity.
你需要解释一下你带领都城守备队的所作所为
You are to explain your doings with the City Watch.
你新组的金袍子
Your new gold cloaks
昨晚干了一番大事  不是吗？
made quite the impression last night, didn't they?
是吗？
Did they?
都城守备队可不是你想挥就挥的剑
The City Watch is not a sword to be wielded at your whim.
他们是国王权力的延伸
They're an extension of the crown.
都城守备等同于执行着国王的法律
The Watch was enforcing the crown's laws.
你不同意吗 斯壮大人？
Wouldn't you agree, Lord Strong?
王子殿下 我不认为……
My Prince, I don't think...
在公众面前肆意展示暴行
Making a public spectacle of wanton brutality
与我们的法律毫无关系
is hardly in line with our laws.
全境各地的贵族
Nobles from every corner of the realm
而今都将聚集在君临
are right now descending upon King's Landing
来参加我哥哥的比武大会
for my brother's tourney.
你难道想这些贵族被抢劫 被强暴 被谋杀吗？
Do you want them mugged, raped, murdered?
除非你离开红堡的安全地带 才会知道这些
You mightn't know this unless you left the safety of the Red Keep
君临的大部分地区 在老百姓眼里都是
but much of King's Landing is seen by the smallfolk
无法无天的可怕去处
as lawless and terrifying.
我们的城市应该让所有人感到安全
Our city should be safe for all its people.
我同意
I agree.
我只是希望你不要把我的都城中一半的人弄残就能实现这点
I just hope you don't have to maim half of my city to achieve this.
时间会证明一切
Time will tell.
我们任命戴蒙王子为司令
We installed Prince Daemon as commander
来改善法律和秩序
to promote law and order.
犯罪分子理当惧怕都城守备队
The criminal element should fear the City Watch.
谢谢你的支持 科利斯伯爵
Thank you for your support, Lord Corlys.
倘若王子能对他的夫人
If only the Prince would show the same devotion
像对工作一样热情就好了 陛下
to his lady wife as he does his work, Your Grace.
你很久没有去谷地或符石城了
You've not been seen in the Vale or at Runestone for quite some time.
我不去那边 我的青铜婊子可能更开心些
I think my bronze bitch is happier for my absence.
雷娅夫人是你的妻子
Lady Rhea is your wife.
一位善良可敬的谷地女士
A good and honorable lady of the Vale.
在谷地 听说男人操羊而不是女人
In the Vale, men are said to fuck sheep instead of women.
我敢向你保证 羊美多了
I can assure you, the sheep are prettier.
天哪
Dear me.
你在七神面前发过誓 在婚姻中会尊重你的妻子
You made a vow before the Seven to honor your wife in marriage.
那么我很乐意将雷娅夫人送给你 海塔尔伯爵
Well, I'd gladly give Lady Rhea to you, Lord Hightower
如果你需要女人暖床的话
if you're in want of a woman to warm your bed.
你的妻子刚好最近过世
Your own lady wife passed recently.
不是吗？
Did she not?
奥托
Otto.
也许你还没从悲伤中走出来
Perhaps you aren't ready to move on just yet.
你知道我弟弟总喜欢刺激你
You know how my brother makes sport of provoking you.
你非得上当吗？
Must you indulge him?
我的错 陛下
My apologies, Your Grace.
御前会议可是花了大价钱
This council has, at great expense
才将都城守备队改善到你要求的标准
bettered the City Watch to your exacting standards.
执行我的法律 但要明白
Enforce my laws, but understand
如果再有昨晚那样的行动 将会受到惩罚
any further performances like last night's will be answered.
知道了 陛下
Understood, Your Grace.
我祖母去世后 君临治安每况愈下
King's Landing has been in decline since my grandmother passed.
到头来
In the end
这个新的都城守备队可能是个好事
this new City Watch might be a good thing.
是什么惹你心烦 我的王子？
What troubles you, my Prince?
我可以再叫来一个人
I could bring in another.
或者找个处女
Perhaps a maiden.
我有好几个
I have several.
甚至可以安排个银发姑娘
I could even arrange one with silver hair.
你是戴蒙·坦格利安
You are Daemon Targaryen.
科拉克休的骑手 暗黑姐妹的持有者
Rider of Caraxes. Wielder of Dark Sister.
国王无法找人取代你
The King cannot replace you.
欢迎！
Be welcome!
我知道你们很多人为了参加这次比武大会
I know many of you have traveled long leagues
都远道而来
to be at these games
但我保证 你们不会失望的
but I promise, you will not be disappointed.
当我看着名单中这些优秀的骑士时
When I look at the fine knights in these lists
我看到了一群无可匹敌的勇士
I see a group without equal in our histories.
而且这个伟大的日子还有更多吉兆
And this great day has been made more auspicious
我很开心地宣布这个消息
by the news that I am happy to share.
爱玛王后已经开始分娩了！
Queen Aemma has begun her labors!
愿七神的好运降临在所有参赛者身上！
May the luck of the Seven shine upon all combatants!
一个神秘骑士？
A mystery knight?
不 科尔家的人 来自风暴地
No, a Cole, of the Stormlands.
我从没听说过科尔家族
I've never heard of House Cole.
雷妮丝·坦格利安公主！
Princess Rhaenys Targaryen!
我在此恭请无冕女王的信物
I would humbly ask for the favor of The Queen Who Never Was.
祝你好运 老表
Good fortune to you, cousin.
如果我需要好运的话 会乐意接受它的
I would gladly take it if I thought I needed it.
就冲这番话 你可以把拜拉席恩的舌头割下来
You could have Baratheon's tongue for that.
舌头又不会改变继承人
Tongues will not change the succession.
随他去吧
Let them wag.
史铎克渥斯伯爵的女儿
Lord Stokeworth's daughter
已经被许给了那个塔利家的年轻侍从
is promised to that young Tarly squire.
马赛伯爵的儿子？
Lord Massey's son?
等他获得骑士头衔 便会完婚
They're to be married as soon as he wins his knighthood.
最好快点
Best get on with it.
我听说埃萝小姐
I heard that Lady Elinor
努力藏着裙子下面隆起的肚子
is hiding a swollen belly beneath her dress.
你对克里斯顿·科尔爵士了解多少 哈罗德爵士？
What do you know about this Ser Criston Cole, Ser Harrold?
我听说克里斯顿爵士出身平民 是唐德利恩伯爵管家的儿子
I'm told Ser Criston is common-born, son of Lord Dondarrion's steward.
除了这个 以及他刚刚把
But other than that, and the fact that he's just unhorsed
拜拉席恩家的两个孩子打下马的事实 我就不知道了
both of the Baratheon lads, I really couldn't say.
坦格利安家族的戴蒙王子
Prince Daemon of House Targaryen!
首都亲王即将选择他的第一位对手
Prince of the City will now choose his first opponent!
戴蒙·坦格利安的第一位对手是——
For his first challenge, Prince Daemon Targaryen chooses
旧镇的加尔温·海塔尔爵士 首相的长子
Ser Gwayne Hightower of Oldtown, eldest son of the Hand of the King.
五金龙押戴蒙
Five dragons on Daemon.
- 干得漂亮 叔叔 - 谢谢你 公主
- Nicely done, Uncle. - Thank you, Princess.
我敢说 我胜券在握 阿莉森小姐
Now, I'm fairly certain I can win these games, Lady Alicent.
得到你的信物会让我如虎添翼
Having your favor would all but assure it.
祝你好运 王子
Good luck, my Prince.
用力！
Come on!
怎么回事？
What's happening?
陛下 胎儿是臀位
The infant is in breech, Your Grace.
所有扶正胎位的尝试都失败了
All attempts to turn the babe have failed.
别干看着啊！
Do something for her!
我们已经给了她很多罂粟花奶
We've given her as much milk of the poppy as we can
再加量孩子就有危险
without risking the child.
王后是位坚强的女性
Your Queen is a strong woman.
她已经拼劲全力了 但恐怕还是不行
She's fighting with all her might, but it may not be enough.
不！
No!
艾玛
Aemma.
艾玛 我在的
Aemma, I'm here.
我在
I'm here.
有我在 没事的
I'm here. It's all right.
- 没事的 - 我不想继续了
- It's all right. - I don't wanna do this.
你不会有事的
You're going to be all right.
不会有事的
抓住我的手
Hold my hand.
杀了他！
Kill him!
真是越来越难看了
And the day grows ugly.
真不知是否应该用这样的方式
I wonder if this is how we should celebrate
来庆祝王储的诞生
the birth of our future king.
如此挥霍暴力
With wanton violence.
梅葛国王死后 已经过了七十年
It's been 70 years since King Maegor's end.
这群骑士都嫩得像夏天的青草
These knights are as green as summer grass.
他们都没见识过真正的战争
None have known real war.
封君把他们送到比武场上
Their lords sent them to the tourney field
手中握剑精力充沛 胯下宝剑也是干劲十足
with fists full of steel and balls full of seed
而我们还指望他们表现得荣誉而优雅
and we expect them to act with honor and grace.
这一滴血没引发战争就已经是奇迹了
It's a marvel that war didn't break out at first blood.
梅罗斯？
Mellos?
陛下
Your Grace.
请来一下
If you would.
难产的时候
During a difficult birth
父亲有时候不得不
it sometimes becomes necessary for the father
做出艰难抉择
to make an impossible choice.
说吧
Well, speak it.
是牺牲一个 还是一尸两命
To sacrifice one or to lose them both.
有保住孩子的可能
There is a chance that we can save the child.
学城教授过一件技艺
A technique is taught at the Citadel
可以直接剖开子宫
which involves cutting directly into the womb
取出婴儿
to free the infant.
- 但伴随的失血…… - 七层地狱 梅罗斯
- But the resulting blood loss... - Seven Hells, Mellos.
你能保住孩子？
You can save the child?
必须立刻行动 否则就只能托付诸神了
We must either act now or leave it with the gods.
克里斯顿·科尔爵士的长枪比武对手
Ser Criston Cole will now tilt
是戴蒙·坦格利安 首都亲王！
against Ser Daemon Targaryen, Prince of the City!
枪！
Lance!
- 韦赛里斯 - 我在
- Viserys. - Yes?
他们现在要把孩子取出来了
They're going to bring the babe out now.
我爱你
I love you.
- 怎么了？ - 没事的
- What is happening? - No, it's all right.
不要 怎么了？
No, what is happening?
- 韦赛里斯 怎么…… - 没事的
- Viserys, what... - No, it's all right.
- 你们要干什么？ - 他们要把孩子取出来
- What are you doing? - They're going to bring the babe out.
他们怎么……
How are they...
- 没事的 - 韦赛里斯 求你了
- It's all right. - Viserys, please...
- 没事的 - 不 我害怕
- It's all right. - No, I'm scared.
- 别怕 - 怎么回事啊？
- Don't be scared. - What is happening?
别害怕 他们要取出孩子
Don't be scared. They're going to bring the babe out.
- 哦不 - 没事的
- Oh no. - It's all right.
他们要取出孩子
They're going to bring the babe out.
不 不要！
No... no!
我要在这里切第一刀
I'm making the first incision.
不 不！
No... no!
韦赛里斯 别这样！求你了！
Viserys, no! Please!
- 不……不要！ - 别怕
- No... no! - Don't be scared.
剑！
Sword!
戴蒙·坦格利安王子
Prince Daemon Targaryen
希望继续徒步比武！
wishes to continue in a contest of arms!
投降吧
Yield.
投降
诸神啊！他是多恩人
Gods. He's Dornish.
我希望得到公主的信物
I was hoping to ask for the Princess's favor.
祝你好运 克里斯顿爵士
I wish you luck, Ser Criston.
公主
Princess.
祝贺您 陛下
Congratulations, Your Grace.
您有儿子了
You have a son.
是男孩？
It's a boy?
新的继承人 陛下
A new heir, Your Grace.
您和王后起好名字了吗？
Had you and the Queen chosen a name?
贝尔隆
Baelon.
他们都在等你
They're waiting for you.
我在想 我弟弟活着的那几个小时里
Ñurho valonqro paghyro jēdunna,
父亲是否终于体会到了幸福
lo tolijī kepa ñuha kirimvī rhēdos pendan...?
你父亲需要你
Kepa aōha avy sīr
比以往任何时候更甚
ojūdo tubiro toliot jorrāelza.
但我永远都无法成为他的儿子
Trēsy dōrī kesan.
龙焰
Dracarys.
- 雷妮拉呢？- 陛下
- Where's Rhaenyra? - Your Grace.
在这黑暗的时刻 我们极其不愿讨论这件事
This is the last thing any of us wish to discuss
但我认为事关紧要
at this dark hour, but I consider the matter urgent.
什么事？
What matter?
继承人的事
That of your succession.
刚发生的两件悲剧
These recent tragedies
使您失去了明确的继承人
have left you without an obvious heir.
国王有继承人 首相大人
The King has an heir, my Lord Hand.
尽管现在是难受的时候 陛下
Despite how difficult this time is, Your Grace
我认为极有必要确定继承人
I feel it important the succession be firmly in place
以维护王国的稳定
for the stability of the realm.
继承人早已根据惯例和律法选定
The succession is already set by precedent and by law.
不妨说出他的名字？
Shall we say his name?
戴蒙·坦格利安
Daemon Targaryen.
如果依然让戴蒙作为无可争议的继承人
If Daemon were to remain the uncontested heir
可能带来王国的动荡
it could destabilize the realm.
王国？还是御前会议？
The realm? Or this council?
在座诸位谁都不知道戴蒙会成为什么样的国王
No one here can know what Daemon would do were he king
但没人会怀疑他的野心
but no one can doubt his ambition.
看看他用金袍子干了什么
Look at what he did with the gold cloaks.
都城守备队对他忠心耿耿
The City Watch is fiercely loyal to him.
- 一支两千人的军队 - 一支你给他的军队 奥托
- An army 2,000 strong. - An army you gave him, Otto.
我任命戴蒙为法务大臣 你说他是个暴君
I named Daemon Master of Laws, but you said he was a tyrant.
任命他为财政大臣
As Master of Coin
你说他挥霍无度 会让国家破产
you said he was a spendthrift that would beggar the realm.
让戴蒙去领导都城守备队正是你的解决之道！
Putting Daemon in command of the City Watch was your solution!
是权宜之计 陛下
A half-measure, Your Grace.
事实是 戴蒙应该远离宫廷
The truth is, Daemon should be far away from this court.
戴蒙是我的弟弟
Daemon is my brother.
我的血亲
My blood.
他会在我的宫中有一席之地
And he will have his place at my court.
那就给他在宫中留下一席之地吧 陛下
Let him keep his place at court, Your Grace
但如果七神将更多悲剧降临到您身上
but if the gods should visit some further tragedy on you
- 有意无意之间…… - “有意”？
- either by design or accident... - "Design"?
你是什么意思？
What are you saying?
我弟弟会杀死我 夺走王位？
My brother would murder me, take my crown?
是吗？
Are you?
拜托
Please.
戴蒙是有野心 没错 但不是觊觎铁王座
Daemon has ambition, yes, but not for the throne.
他对这事没有耐心
He lacks the patience for it.
诸神还没有创造出
The gods have yet to make a man
一个对绝对权力没有耐心的人呢 陛下
who lacks the patience for absolute power, Your Grace.
在这种情况下 国王指定一个继承人
Under such circumstances, it would not be an aberration
倒也不算脱离常规
for the King to name a successor.
那么 还有谁有资格呢？
Well, who else would have a claim?
国王的第一个孩子
The King's firstborn child.
雷妮拉？一个女孩？
Rhaenyra? A girl?
铁王座上从没坐过女王
No queen has ever sat the Iron Throne.
这只是依据传统和先例罢了 斯壮大人
That is only by tradition and precedent, Lord Strong.
如果御前会议这么关心秩序和稳定
If order and stability so concerns this council
那么我们或许不应该打破百年来的传统
then perhaps we shouldn't break 100 years of it
让一个女孩成为王嗣
by naming a girl heir.
戴蒙会成为第二个梅葛 甚至更糟
Daemon would be a second Maegor, or worse.
他冲动而又暴力
He is impulsive and violent.
保护国王和他的王国不受戴蒙侵害
It is the duty of this council
正是我们这个御前会议的责任
to protect the King and the realm from him.
抱歉 陛下 但这恐怕不是我所看到的真相
I'm sorry, Your Grace, but that is the truth as I see it
而且我知道这里有人跟我想法一致
and I know that others here agree.
我是不会被迫在我的兄弟和女儿之间做出选择的
I will not be made to choose between my brother and my daughter.
您不必如此 陛下
You wouldn't have to, Your Grace.
还有其他人选
There are others who would have a claim.
比如你的夫人？科利斯大人
Such as your wife, Lord Corlys?
无冕女王？
The Queen Who Never Was?
雷妮丝是杰赫里斯一世长子的独女
Rhaenys was the only child of Jaehaerys' eldest son.
她在大议会时拥有很强的继承权主张
She had a strong claim at the Great Council
而且她已经有了一位男性继承人
and she already has a male heir.
就在刚刚 你才声明支持戴蒙
Just moments ago, you announced your support for Daemon!
如果我们都不能在继承人问题上取得一致 那还怎么指望……
If we cannot agree on an heir, then how can we expect……
我的妻儿都死了!
My wife and son are dead!
我不要再坐在这里忍受你们这群享用遗体的乌鸦!
I will not sit here and suffer crows that come to feast on their corpses!
派只渡鸦到旧镇去 马上
Send a raven to Oldtown. Straight away.
小姐
My Lady.
亲爱的
My darling.
雷妮拉怎么样了？
How's Rhaenyra?
她失去了母亲
She lost her mother.
王后一直受所有人爱戴
The Queen has been well-loved by all.
今天我也想起了你的母亲
I found myself thinking of your own mother today.
- 陛下怎么样了？- 非常低落
- How is His Grace? - Very low.
所以我叫你来
Which is why I sent for you.
我认为你该去找他 安慰他
I thought you might go to him, offer him comfort.
去他房间？
In his chambers?
我不知道该说些什么
I wouldn't know what to say.
别咬了
Stop that.
他会很开心有人去看他
He'll be glad of a visitor.
可以穿条你母亲的裙子
You might wear one of your mother's dresses.
陛下 阿莉森·海塔尔小姐求见
The Lady Alicent Hightower, Your Grace.
什么事 阿莉森？
What is it, Alicent?
我觉得该来看看您 陛下
I thought I might come and look in on you, Your Grace.
我带来了一本书
I brought a book.
真体贴 谢谢你
That's very kind, thank you.
这是我最爱的一本书
It's a favorite of mine.
我知道您有多热衷历史
I do know how passionate you are for the histories.
是的
Yes, I am.
我母亲离世的时候
When my mother died
人们只会拐弯抹角地和我说话
people only ever spoke to me in riddles.
而我想要的 只是有人能对我的遭遇
All I wanted was for someone to say that they were sorry
表示难过
for what happened to me.
我很难过 陛下
I'm very sorry, Your Grace.
谢谢
Thank you.
再次成为国王的唯一继承人
The King's sole heir once again.
不为我们的未来干一杯吗？
Might we drink to our future?
安静！
Quiet!
让王子来说几句！
Your Prince will speak!
安静！
Silence!
陛下 在我们开始会议之前
Before we begin, Your Grace
有必要分享我收到的一封密报
I have a report I feel compelled to share.
昨晚
Last night
戴蒙王子买断了丝绸街上的
Prince Daemon bought out one of the pleasure houses
一家青楼
on the Street of Silk
来款待都城守备队的士官
to entertain officers of the City Watch
以及他的一些朋友
and other friends of his.
国王和御前会议一直对我王位继承人的身份
King and Council have long rued my position
心生芥蒂
as next in line for the throne.
但随便他们怎么做梦和祈祷 我的位置看来不那么容易被取代
But dream and pray as they all might, it seems I'm not so easily replaced.
诸神一手给予 一手剥夺
The gods give just as the gods take away.
他为贝尔隆王子举杯
He toasted Prince Baelon.
敬国王之子
To the King's son.
称他为……
Styling him...
一日王储
the Heir for a Day.
我和三名不同的证人确认了这份密报
I corroborated this report with three separate witnesses.
所有证据都表明 那晚是一场庆祝活动
The evening was, by all accounts, a celebration.
哥哥 你真是一副征服者的派头
You cut the image of the Conqueror, brother.
你说过吗？
Did you say it?
我不知道你指什么
I don't know what you mean.
你该称呼我为“陛下”
You will address me as "Your Grace"
否则我会让御林铁卫割下你的舌头
or I will have my Kingsguard cut out your tongue.
“一日王储” 你说过吗？
"The Heir for a Day." Did you say it?
我们都用自己的方式哀悼 陛下
We must all mourn in our own way, Your Grace.
我的家庭刚毁了
My family has just been destroyed.
你却没待在我身边 或者雷妮拉身边
But instead of being by my side, or Rhaenyra's
而是选择去庆祝自己的晋升！
you chose to celebrate your own rise!
跟你的婊子和马屁精一起寻欢作乐！
Laughing with your whores and your lickspittles!
你在宫廷之上除了我没有其他盟友！
You have no allies at court but me!
我一直在维护你！
I have only ever defended you!
然而我给你的一切 你都弃之如敝屣扔回给了我
Yet everything I've given you, you've thrown back in my face.
你只想把我赶走
You've only ever tried to send me away.
去谷地 去都城守备队 去那些远离你的地方
To the Vale, to the City Watch, anywhere but by your side.
你已经当了十年国王
Ten years you've been king
但你从未要求我做你的国王之手！
and yet not once have you asked me to be your Hand!
- 我为什么要那么做？ - 因为我是你的弟弟
- Why would I do that? - Because I'm your brother.
龙血浓于水
And the blood of the dragon runs thick.
那你为什么要伤我这么深？
Then why do you cut me so deeply?
我说的只是真相 我看得出奥托·海塔尔的本来面目
I've only ever spoken the truth. I see Otto Hightower for what he is.
- 一位忠贞不移的国王之手？ - 一个婊子
- An unwavering and loyal Hand? - A cunt.
一个次子 没法继承任何东西
A second son who stands to inherit nothing
除非自己争取
he doesn't seize for himself.
奥托·海塔尔是一个值得尊敬的人
Otto Hightower is a more honorable man
- 你这辈子也赶不上 - 他没有保护你
- than you could ever be. - He doesn't protect you.
- 而我可以 - 从谁手中保护？
- I would. - From what?
你自己
Yourself.
你是个懦弱的人 韦赛里斯
You're weak, Viserys.
那些御前会议的水蛭都知道这一点
And that council of leeches knows it.
他们都为了自己的利益寄生在你身上
They all prey on you for their own ends.
我已决定任命一位新的继承人
I have decided to name a new heir.
- 我就是你的继承人 - 不再是了
- I'm your heir. - Not anymore.
你要即刻回到符石城 回到你夫人身边
You are to return to Runestone and your lady wife at once
这是国王的旨意 不得质疑
and you are to do so without quarrel by order of your King.
遵命 陛下
Your Grace.
父亲
Father.
贝勒里恩是最后一个见证过
Balerion was the last living creature
末日浩劫之前的瓦雷利亚的生物
to have seen Old Valyria before the Doom.
见证过它的伟大与阴暗
Its greatness and its flaws.
当你凝视龙的时候 看到了什么？
When you look at the dragons, what do you see?
什么？
What?
自从母亲葬礼后你再没和我说过一句话
You haven't spoken a word to me since Mother's funeral
而现在你派御林铁卫来……
and now you send your Kingsguard down...
回答我
Answer me.
这很重要
It's important.
你看到了什么？
What do you see?
- 我感觉就像看到了我们自己 - 告诉我
- I suppose I see us. - Tell me.
每个人都说坦格利安比凡人更接近诸神
Everyone says Targaryens are closer to gods than to men
但他们那么说是因为我们的龙
but they say that because of our dragons.
没有龙 我们泯然众人
Without them, we're just like everyone else.
那种以为我们能控制龙的观念 只是假象
The idea that we control the dragons is an illusion.
龙的力量不是凡人可以随意玩弄操控的
They're a power man should never have trifled with.
它带来了瓦雷利亚末日浩劫
One that brought Valyria its doom.
如果我们不审视自己的历史 它也会给我们带来同样的后果
If we don't mind our own histories, it will do the same to us.
坦格利安必须明白这一点 才能成为国王……
Targaryen must understand this to be King...
……或者女王
or Queen.
我很抱歉 雷妮拉
I'm sorry, Rhaenyra.
自从你出生以来 我浪费了很多时光
I have wasted the years since you were born
一直苦苦求子
wanting for a son.
你继承了你母亲最好的一面
You are the very best of your mother.
我坚信 我知道她也坚信
And I believe it, I know she did
你会成为一位伟大的女王
that you could be a great ruling queen.
戴蒙是你的继承人
Daemon is your heir.
戴蒙不是国王的料子
Daemon was not made to wear the crown.
但我相信你是
But I believe that you were.
瓦列利安家族的科利斯
Corlys of House Velaryon
潮汐之主 潮头岛伯爵
Lord of the Tides and Master of Driftmark.
我 科利斯·瓦列利安
I, Corlys Velaryon
潮汐之主 潮头岛伯爵
Lord of the Tides and Master of Driftmark
承诺忠于韦赛里斯国王
promise to be faithful to King Viserys
和他任命的继承人雷妮拉公主
and his named heir, the Princess Rhaenyra.
我向他们宣誓效忠
I pledge fealty to them
尽忠护主 竭力御敌
and shall defend them against all enemies
一片忠心 绝无欺瞒
in good faith and without deceit.
誓言为证 新旧诸神
I swear this by the old gods and the new.
这不是小事 雷妮拉
This is no trivial gesture, Rhaenyra.
龙鞍是一码事
A dragon's saddle is one thing
但铁王座才是全国最危险的位置
but the Iron Throne is the most dangerous seat in the realm.
我 霍巴特·海塔尔伯爵
I, Lord Hobert Hightower
南境灯塔 学城守护者
Beacon of the South, Defender of the Citadel
旧镇之音
and Voice of Oldtown
承诺忠于韦赛里斯国王
promise to be faithful to King Viserys
和他任命的继承人雷妮拉公主
and his named heir, the Princess Rhaenyra.
我向他们宣誓效忠
I pledge fealty to them
尽忠护主 竭力御敌
and shall defend them against all enemies
一片忠心 绝无欺言
in good faith and without deceit.
誓言为证 新旧诸神
I swear this by the old gods and the new.
伸手
Give me your hand.
我 博蒙德·拜拉席恩
I, Boremund Baratheon
承诺忠于韦赛里斯国王
promise to be faithful to King Viserys.
我还有事得告诉你
There's something else that I need to tell you.
你理解起来可能有些困难
It might be difficult for you to understand
但一定要仔细听着
but you must hear it.
我们的历史
Our histories
他们说 伊耿从龙石岛眺望黑水湾对岸
they tell us that Aegon looked across the Blackwater from Dragonstone
看见了一块静待主人的丰饶土地
saw a rich land ripe for the capture.
但驱使他征服的不只是野心
But ambition alone is not what drove him to conquest.
那是一个梦
It was a dream.
正如丹妮思预见到瓦雷里亚的末日
And just as Daenys foresaw the end of Valyria
伊耿预见了人类世界的末日
Aegon foresaw the end of the world of men.
它始于遥远的北方袭来的可怕凛冬
'Tis to begin with a terrible winter gusting out of the distant north.
我 瑞肯·史塔克 临冬城公爵
I, Rickon Stark, Lord of Winterfell...
伊耿看到寒风带来的终极黑暗
Aegon saw absolute darkness riding on those winds.
而栖身其中的东西 会催毁生者的世界
And whatever dwells within will destroy the world of the living.
当大寒冬来临的时候 雷妮拉
When this Great Winter comes, Rhaenyra
所有维斯特洛人都该挺身抗击
all of Westeros must stand against it.
如果人类世界要生存下去
And if the world of men is to survive
就必须有一位坦格利安坐上铁王座
a Targaryen must be seated on the Iron Throne.
一位国王或者女王
A king or queen
强大到足以团结王国对抗寒冷和黑暗
strong enough to unite the realm against the cold and the dark.
伊耿把这个梦称作“冰与火之歌”
Aegon called his dream "The Song of Ice and Fire."
这个秘密
This secret
从伊耿时代起 就在国王和王储间口口相传
it's been passed from king to heir since Aegon's time.
现在你必须保证会传承秘密
Now you must promise to carry it
守护秘密
and protect it.
答应我 雷妮拉
Promise me this, Rhaenyra.
答应我
Promise me.
我 韦赛里斯·坦格利安一世
I, Viserys Targaryen, first of his name
安达尔人 洛伊拿人和先民的国王
King of the Andals, and the Rhoynar, and the First Men
七国统治者暨全境守护者
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms, and Protector of the Realm
特此任命
do hereby name
雷妮拉·坦格利安
Rhaenyra Targaryen
为龙石岛公主
Princess of Dragonstone
暨铁王座继承人
and heir to the Iron Throne.